(
"ai_sub_version": "3.5.2",
"generated_at": "2026-08-24T21:43:24.439871",
"lyrics_prompt_version": 9,
"subtitles_prompt_version": 18,
"complete": true,
"max_retries_exceeded": false,
"any_pending": false,
"settings": (
"ai": (
"model": null,
"model_subtitles": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"model_lyrics": "google-gla:gemini-3.5-flash-lite",
"rpm": 4,
"tpm": 250000,
"google": (
"file_cache_ttl": 10,
"use_files_api": true,
"max_storage_gb": 18.0
),
"search": (
"qps": 0.3,
"max_length": 4096,
"web_search_tool": "langsearch",
"timeout": 60.0,
"retries": 3,
"min_wait_seconds": 1.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 10.0,
"multiplier": 2.0
),
"validation_buffer_ms": 2000,
"verification_gap_seconds": 60,
"gap_verification_retries": 1,
"gap_verification_ignore_start": true,
"gap_verification_ignore_end": true
),
"split": (
"max_seconds": 300,
"re_encode": (
"enabled": false,
"fps": 1.0,
"height": 360,
"bitrate_kb": 35,
"threshold_mb": 20,
"duration_tolerance_ms": 100,
"encoder": null
),
"start_offset_min": 0
"thread": (
"uploads": 4,
"re_encode": 2,
"lyrics": 4,
"subtitles": 4
),
"retry": (
"per_run": 5,
"max_runs": 3,
"multiplier": 2.0,
"min_wait_seconds": 30.0,
"max_wait_seconds": 300
),
"log": (
"level": "info",
"timestamps": true,
"scrub": false,
"progress_bars": true,
"progress_bar_width": 80,
"progress_bar_refresh_seconds": 1.0
)
猫又おかゆ わかり手グランプリ！
Nekomata Okayu Wakarite Grand Prix!
はい、ということで皆さんついにこの日がやってきました！
Alright everyone, this day has finally arrived!
猫又おかゆによる猫又好きが参加する猫又おかゆのための企画です！
A special event hosted by Nekomata Okayu for all Nekomata fans!
猫又好きの！
True Nekomata lovers!
皆さん猫又好きですよね？
You guys love Nekomata, right?
大好き、大好き、好き好き好き！
We love her, we love her, love love love!
ありがとうございます。まずは今宵の挑戦者の皆さんを紹介しましょう！
Thank you. First, let's introduce tonight's challengers!
ではまず、大空スバルさん！
Starting with Oozora Subaru!
はい！すばる！なんか気がついたら猫又好きに呼ばれていました！2期生王道スバル！
Hi! Subaru! Somehow I was called a Nekomata fan! Gen 2 royal road Subaru!
今日はどんな人の声よとも全員ボコボコにして1位の座を獲得していきたいと思います！やっほーね！
Today, I'll beat everyone else to a pulp and take the #1 spot! Yay!
おねがいしまーす！
Please treat me well!
では次、みおちゃん！
Next up, Mio-chan!
はい！うち、うち、うちだよ！大神ミオだよ！
Yes! It's me, me, me! Ookami Mio!
みおです！
I'm Mio!
まあね、猫又好きとしてね、参戦させていただきましたが！
Well, I'm participating as a Nekomata fan, but!
まあね、うちはね、おかゆのことよく分かってるというか、まあ、気合い合うことがね、よくあるから！そうそう！
I understand Okayu really well, and our vibes often match! That's right!
優勝しちゃうかもしれないなー！
I might just win this thing!
隣で勝ち誇ってる人が…
The person looking triumphant right next to me...
あれ勝ち誇ってる？
Are they triumphing?
じゃあ、ちょっとよく見たら頭に青筋が浮いているころさん！
Then, looking closely, Korone-san has a vein popping on her head!
なに青筋？これ？あれかな？それかな？
What vein? This? Is it that? Is it this?
あのね、ころねはね、おかゆのこと知ってますから！
You see, Korone knows all about Okayu!
外野よりは、外野よりもおかゆのこと知ってると思うから！アゲ！
I know more about Okayu than anyone in the audience! Age!
よろしくね！
Nice to meet you!
なんですかそれ！
What is that?!
初めて聞いたんだけど！
First time I've ever heard that!
オーケー！はい！よろしくお願いします！
Okay! Yes! Please treat me well!
では、本日は皆さんには世界中の猫又おかゆ好きを代表して、様々な猫又おかゆクイズに挑戦してもらいます！
Today, you'll represent Nekomata Okayu fans worldwide and tackle various Okayu quizzes!
そうですよ！世界代表ですよ、皆さんは！
That's right! You're global representatives!
やった！みおちゃん！
Yay! Mio-chan!
名誉なことで！
It's an honor!
ちょ、雑じゃねえか！
Wait, isn't that sloppy?!
もちろん！正解するぞー！
Of course! We'll get it right!
では、さっそく参りましょう！
Now, let's get right into it!
さっそく？もう？
Right away? Already?
まいっていきますよ
We're going!
ビビってんのか？帰ってもいいんだぞ？
Are you scared? You can go home, you know?
そうなのか？帰るか？帰るか？帰るか？
Is that so? Should we go home? Should we go home?
ダメだ！
No way!
暫定1位はやめてくださいね。
Please stop claiming temporary first place!
暫定1位！
Temporary first place!
はーい、ではやっていきましょう！
Alright, then let's get started!
はーい！
Yay!
では1問目お願いします！
Now, please give us the first question!
おっしゃ！
Let's go!
問題。
Question:
猫又おかゆを漢字で表すなら？
If you were to represent Nekomata Okayu in kanji,
『猫』以外でお答えください。
please answer with something other than "cat."
え？謎々？
Eh? A riddle?
謎々ではないよ。
It's not a riddle.
謎々ではない？え、猫以外でかー。
Not a riddle? Eh, other than "cat"...
猫でしかも自分がこれ答えてるんでしょ？
And besides, I'm the one answering this, right?
どういうこと？
What do you mean?
あ、これはおかゆが答えた答えを当てるってことでしょう？
Ah, that means we have to guess the answer Okayu wrote down, right?
そう！僕が答えた答えだから僕が何て書くかなっていうのを想像して書いてください。
Exactly! Since it's the answer I wrote, please imagine what I would write and write it down.
簡単だよ！
It's easy!
あ、みおちゃんはなんか書いてますね
Ah, Mio-chan has written something down.
なんかこれしかないでしょやっぱおかゆと言えば！
I mean, what else could it be when you talk about Okayu!
なるほどね！おかゆと言えばこれってことだ？
I see! When you say Okayu, that's what it is?
それってことじゃあ…
If that's what it means, then...
これじゃない？
isn't it this?
ああなるほど！なるほどなるほど！
Ah, I see! Makes sense, makes sense!
みおちゃんところさんは書き揃ってますね。
Mio-chan and Korone-san's answers match.
え、待って書いた！
Eh, wait, I wrote it!
何笑ってんだよ！
What are you laughing at?!
何笑ってんだよ！え、違ったの？だって…
What are you laughing at?! Eh, was it wrong? Because...
いやいや、なんか、なんか可愛いなと思って。オプションついてたからさ。
No no, I just thought it was cute. Because it had an option attached.
あ、これにしよう。
Ah, I'll go with this.
あ、皆さん書き終えました？
Ah, did everyone finish writing?
はい、書いた！
Yes, I wrote it!
書き終わった人ー？
Anyone finished writing?
はーい！はーい！
Yes! Yes!
では出揃ったということで解答お願いします！
So, since everyone is ready, please reveal your answers!
お願いします！
Please!
あ、ではスバルちゃんいいですか？発表お願いします！
Ah, then Subaru-chan, are you ready? Please present!
オープン！
Open!
夜！
Night!
これですね！おかゆと言えば夜型！そして
This is it! When you say Okayu, it's night-owl! And,
おかゆはデビュー当時、夜の、なんだっけ？夜の帝王王だったじゃん。
Okayu was, back in her debut days, the king of the night... wait, what was it?
夜の帝王、夜の皇帝じゃん！
King of the night, emperor of the night!
なるほどなるほど！
I see, I see!
夜だ！夜だ！ということで
It's night! It's night! So,
すばるちゃんは夜という回答でしたね。
Subaru-chan's answer was "night."
では次、みおちゃんの回答を見ていきましょう。
Now next, let's look at Mio-chan's answer.
ではみおちゃん、オープン！
Now Mio-chan, open!
お！えー！うわ、その可能性もあったか！
Oh! Ehh! Wow, that possibility existed too!
罪！
Sin!
いや、しかもね、猫又おかゆ裁判の主犯じゃないですけど、主宰はみおちゃんでしたからね。
No, and besides, Nekomata Okayu trial's mastermind... well, not mastermind, but the organizer was Mio-chan.
確かに！血の涙を猫が流している。本当だ。
True! A cat shedding tears of blood. That's true.
裁判、裁判官としてね。
As a trial judge, you know.
でもこう、罪もあるし、罪深いところもあるんだけど、なんかこう、人たらしなところも罪だなと思って。
But like, there's sin, and there are sinful parts, but I thought being a heart-stealer is also a sin.
ああ、なるほどね！そういう、言いようによってはね、罪にしてみました。
Ah, I see! Depending on how you look at it, I made it "sin."
罪にしました おばちの
I made it a sin. Obachi's...
では最後、ころさんお願いします！
Now lastly, Korone-san, please!
はい！
Yes!
お、何これ？
Oh, what is this?
女！女？
Woman! Woman?
ちょっと待って、眉毛、眉毛、違う違う、眉毛が、眉毛が、そこじゃない、そこじゃない、そこじゃない、多分。
Wait a minute, eyebrows, eyebrows, no no, the eyebrows are, the eyebrows are not there, not there, probably.
焦りすぎた！
You rushed too much!
これは、おかゆは、なんかく、ボーイッシュな感じだけれども、やっぱりなんかね、こう、溢れ出る女を隠しきれてないみたいな。
As for this, Okayu has a somewhat boyish vibe, but somehow, she can't hide the overflowing womanliness.
めっちゃ言われてるそれ！
You're being told that so much!
最近はね、あ、これかなって思った。なんせ、ずっと一緒にいるころさんにさ、メスのことって言い切られると、なんか一番
Lately I thought, ah, maybe this is it. Especially since Korone-san, who's always been with me, flatly calls me a female, somehow it feels...
恥ずかしいな。あ、でも、かわいいでで。ありがとう！
embarrassing. Ah, but it's cute. Thank you!
なんかおいっ！お前ら何笑ってんだよ！20分で書いて！
What, hey! What are you laughing at?! Write in 20 minutes!
20分で書かなきゃいけないのかよ！お前は！
Do we have to write it in 20 minutes?! You!
ということで、ではみなさんの回答で揃ったところで、僕の回答を発表したいと思います！
With that said, since everyone's answers are in, I'd like to announce my answer!
正解！
Correct!
馴！
Jun!
馴れ初めだから
Because it's familiarity
はあ？！
Huh?!
なんでそこつけてんだお前は！
Why did you attach that there!
いや、理由としては、結構その、新しい新居に引っ越したりとかしても、すぐ
Well, as for the reason, even if I move into a new place, right away
なんかもう1年前から自分の家に住んでるみたいだな、って気持ちになるから、「馴れ初め」
I feel like I've been living in my own house for a year already, so "familiarity".
馴れ初めそういう感じなのだって。自分の感覚だろそれ！
That's just your own sense!
なおね！なおね！
Naone! Naone!
なんでそんな不服そうなんですか？どうだろころねさん。
Why do you look so displeased? What about it, Korone-san?
え、こん、こんな漢字知らんし、まず。
Eh, I don't even know this kanji, first of all.
漢字のレパートリー少なくないだからさ、ちょっと難しい感じだったね。
Your kanji repertoire is small, so it was a slightly difficult kanji.
でもおかゆは知性高めだからな、確かに。
But Okayu's intelligence is on the higher side, true.
え、ちょっとこの、あれかわいいな。
Eh, but this one is cute.
ほらだってこんなおってるじゃん！え？見て！
Look, because she's holding it like this! Eh? Look!
あれ？なんかさ、ぐにゃぐにゃの毛みたいなの載ってるけど、大丈夫？
Wait, it's got some squiggly hair drawn on it. Is that really okay?
草！
Lol!
毛を働か、こんな大体で働きやすいいのさ！そうだよ！さっき見られてたぞ！
Working with hair... Working with roughly drawn stuff is fine, right? Exactly, we were looking at it earlier!
ということでね、皆さん、全員不正解ということで、全然、全然わかってないよー！
So everyone, you all got it wrong. That means none of you understood at all!
難しいなー、なんか！
That's difficult! So hard!
はい、猫又おゆの座右の銘は？
Next question! What is Nekomata Okayu's motto?
ええー！？座右の銘はあ？
Eh?! Okayu's motto?
それこそざっき…あれ？ええ？
That's right, Zaggi... Wait, eh?
どうかな？どうかな？
Is it right? Is it right?
座右の銘超難しいじゃん！
A motto is super difficult!
うわ、でもなんか言ってた気がする！でもなんだっけな…！
But I feel like she said it before! But what was it again...?
え？言ってた？言ってたの？なんかヒント！いや、でももう何も思い出せないけど…
Eh? She said it? She said it? Any hints? Well, I can't remember anything anymore...
それっぽいこと言ってた気がする！
But I feel like you said something like that!
本当！？結局何も思い出してないじゃん、それは！
Really? You didn't remember a single thing, did you?
それっぽいこと今言っただけで何も思い出してないからね！
You just said something that sounded about right, you didn't remember anything!
本当だぜ！なんだろう！
That's right! What could it be?
え、座右の銘って何？
Wait, what is a motto anyway?
座右の銘、例えば、生きてきて、こういう言葉を胸にね。
A motto is, for example, living your life with words like this close to your heart...
はいはいはいはいはい！
Yes, yes, yes, yes, yes!
ええーー！？
Eeeh?!
そういう話ですよ。
That kind of story.
この言葉を…
This word...
まあ、思い浮かばなかったらさ、ころさん自分の好きな言葉が私の好きな言葉かもしれないじゃん。
Well, if you can't think of one, maybe Korone's favorite words are my favorite words too.
あ、なるほど！わかった。
Ah, I see. Got it.
みおちゃんどうかな？これだ！
Mio-chan, how about you? This is it!
おお、難しいな！
Oh, this is tough!
まず座右の銘自体がもう頭まっしろで何も思いつかないんだよね。
First of all, the very idea of a motto blanks my mind completely, I can't think of anything.
なるほど、なるほど！なんだろうなあ！
I see, I see! What could it be?
これだ、もう100発100中よ！
This is it, 100% spot on!
本当に！？
Really?!
あ、スバルちゃん書き終わってますね！
Ah, Subaru-chan has finished writing!
これです。
This is it.
なるほど、なるほど。
I see, I see.
自信がある！
Feeling confident!
自信ありだそうです。
She says she has confidence.
まじか！
Seriously?!
自信が…自信ありですね！
Confidence... She has confidence, then!
さあ、2人はどうでしょうか！
Now, how about the other two?
今から書くよ。お、なんか書き始めてる。
We'll write now. Oh, she's starting to write.
お？なんか全部ひらがなで書いてる！
Oh? She's writing everything in hiragana!
ひらがな。なるほど、なるほど。
Hiragana. I see, I see.
なるほどね！はいはいはい。
I see! Yes, yes, yes.
だいぶで揃ってきましたよ！
We've pretty much got everything ready!
スバルちゃんとみおちゃんは書き終わってますね。
Subaru-chan and Mio-chan have finished writing, right?
そうですね。
That's right.
なにこれ！OKよ！
What is this? It's okay!
めっちゃ長くない！？めっちゃ長んだけど！
Isn't that way too long?! That's way too long!
ちょっと待って！よく見ると、長すぎて今。あ、でも座右の銘ってさ、そんな長くないけ？知らんけど。待って、ひらがな。
Wait, looking closely, it's so long! Wait, aren't mottos usually shorter? I don't know. Wait, it's all in hiragana!
では、さらさらね、皆さんの書いている回答を見ていきたいと思います。
Well then, let's take a look at everyone's written answers.
こちらです。
Here it is.
沈黙は金、有弁は銀！あーなるほど！
Silence is golden, eloquence is silver! Ah, I see, I see.
これはですね、あの、よく言ってます、お粥が実際。
This is... well, Okayu actually says this all the time!
こう、通話とかしてても、いや、やっぱりねスバルちゃん、沈黙は金、有弁は銀なんだよね。
Like, even during calls, "Well, you know Subaru-chan, silence is golden, eloquence is silver."
待って！お粥、そんなこと言われたことないよ！
Wait! Okayu, you've never said anything like that!
え、でもそんなこと言われたことないよ！
Even if you say so, you've never said that!
どっちかっていうと、スバルちゃんが、やっぱさ、有弁は銀なんだよねって言って、そうだよ、沈黙は金だねって言う、いつもの。
If anything, Subaru would say, "Well, eloquence is silver after all," and then Okayu would say, "And silence is golden, right?" That's how it always goes.
サポートじゃん！
That's the support!
サポートじゃん、それは！
That was just you supporting her!
限定だったかも！
That might have been a special case!
いや、違うよそれ！どっちかっていうと、
No, that's wrong! If anything,
スバルちゃんの座右の銘な気がするけどね！
It feels more like Subaru-chan's motto!
じゃあそれもう間違いじゃん！違うじゃん！
Then that's wrong! That's not it!
いや、まだわかんないけどね！じゃあ間違いじゃん！ええー！？
Well, we don't know yet! Then it's wrong! Eeeh?!
まあね、でもまあ、これかも知れない。そうかも知れないからね。
Well, yeah, but this could be it. It's possible, after all.
では、みおちゃんの回答を見てみましょう！
Now let's take a look at Mio-chan's answer!
こちらです。
Here it is.
明日は我が身。
Misfortune visits everyone.
これこそさ、スバルちゃんの座右の銘じゃない！？
Isn't that Subaru-chan's motto?!
ええ！？なんでなんでそんな！確かに！スバルめっちゃ言う！
Huh?! Why is that?! True! Subaru says that a lot!
明日は我が身って、おおかゆのわりみせにしきがあったかな？もしかしたら、スバルわりみせしきじゃないですかね。
"Misfortune visits everyone" - did Okayu have that as her motto, or did Subaru just say it so much?
これよく、あれ？スバルちゃ……
Maybe this is... Wait, Subaru-chan!
スバルちゃんがいつも言ってる、言ってる、言ってるよ！えば、「明日は我が身」って！
Subaru-chan is always saying, "Misfortune visits everyone!"
よい言ってる！言うよ！これ！
She always says it! She really does!
どう、どんなときに言ってるんだっけ？
Wait, when does she even say that?
いや、「明日は我が身だよな！」って言って
She's like, "Misfortune could visit me tomorrow!"
確かに、ことあるごとにね。うん。
True, every time something happens, yeah.
言ってる言ってる！まあでもおかゆが言ってるかもね。
She says it! Well, maybe Okayu says it too.
え、待って、じゃあさ、それも間違いってことじゃん。これでなってるかもよ？
Wait, then that means that's wrong too, right? Could this be it?
ええ！？本当！？見せてよ！
Seriously?! Show us!
ころさんの回答に期待してみましょう。では、どん！
Let's see what Korone-san came up with. Here it comes, boom!
なにこれ！かなしいこともいっぱいあるけど、それは全部、
What is this?! There are lots of sad things, but they're all...
この先の幸せのためなんだ。だから大丈夫！
...for future happiness! So it's okay!
かなしいこともいっぱいあるけど、それはぜんぶ
A lot of sad things happen, but...
この先のしあわせのためなんだ。
this is all for the sake of your future!
だから大丈夫！
So it's okay!
それじゃあ、「しじょう」じゃなくて「しじょん」じゃん。
That's not "so it's okay"! That's shijou!
しじょん？
Shijon?
それじゃあないの。ボエみじゃん、ボエみ。
That's not shijou! Boy mi, boy mi!
なんもじ、なんもじまでおさまれば、至上の名ににしていいわけ。
If you fit all the letters, it can become "shijou no mei."
いや、でも
Yeah, but...
なんか有名な人が放った言葉みたいな感じだよね。
It's like something a famous person said.
そうそうそうそうそう。
Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
それ誰が放った言葉なの？
Whose quote is that?
光ねかな。
Mitsuo?
あ、オリジン。起源ってこと？
Ah, origin, origin?
みつお？
Mitsuo?
みつおだよ！
Mitsuo!
オリジンなの？
It's Mitsuo!
ちょっとみつおっぽいけどね。
It's kind of like Mitsuo, though.
みつおだよ、それは。
Mitsuo!
それわ、みつおさんでしょ。
That's Mitsuo Aida!
みつお。
Mitsuo!
いや、みつおさん付けねえだろ。
Don't put honorifics on Mitsuo!
違うだろ、そこは。
That's different, man.
ではね、正解の方に行きましょうか。
Well then, let's go to the correct answer.
この中に正解してる人はいるのか。
Is anyone among us correct?
それでは正解お願いします。
Let's see the correct answer, please.
せーの、
Ready...
どん！
Don!
せーの、
Ready...
どん！
Don!
だーん！
Ta-da!
なかなか来ない感じですね、これは。
Well, that's pretty hard to come by, isn't it?
あ、出てきた！
Oh, it came out!
なにこれ？
What is this?
塞翁が馬。
"Saio ga uma."
どういう意味ですか？
What does that mean?
サイオンがウマってことないです。
It doesn't mean "Saio is a horse."
あ、これは
Well, this is...
たとえば、いい自転車が半額で買えたと。で、その自転車に乗ってたら転んじゃったと。
For example, you buy a cheap bicycle, and while riding it, you crash.
でも転んだことによって得られたいいこともあるっていう、そのいいことなんだ けど、一概にいいこととも言えないし、悪いこととも言えないねっていう
But crashing brings some good things too, so it's hard to say if it's completely good or completely bad.
そういうやつです。
It's that kind of thing.
へえ。
I see.
はい、どうぞ。さっきからちょっと内容が難しすぎた気がします。
Well then, the content has been a bit too difficult since a while ago, I feel.
はい、どうぞ。IQが釣り合っていません。
Your IQs don't match!
いやいや、そんなことないよ！
No way, that's not true!
ほら、「ころぬ」なんて全部ひらがなで書いてるじゃないですか。
Come on, "koronu" is all written in hiragana!
全部じゃない、全部じゃない！
Not all of it! Not all of it!
「大丈夫」とかは漢字で書いた。
"Daijoubu" is written in kanji!
確かにね。
That's true.
なんだよ。
What is this?
じゃあ仮にみんなのその何、感覚に下げたとしても
So, even if everyone's feelings were lowered a bit,
やきにく定食とかになっちゃうんだじゃない？
it would end up being a yakiniku set meal or something, wouldn't it?
バカにされてる。
Are you making fun of me?
はい、じゃあ次の問題に行きましょう！
Well then, let's go to the next question!
次の問題、どうぞ。
Next question, please.
問題。
Question:
猫又おかゆの「デビューしてから1番嬉しかった出来事」は？
What was Nekomata Okayu's happiest moment since her debut?
デビューしてから1番嬉しかったこと？
Since your debut, the moment you were happiest...
これは、え、聞いてちょっと、どうぞ。
This is... Hey, listen for a bit.
ヒントが欲しいね。ヒントが欲しいです。
We want a hint!
ちょっと待って、僕なんて答えか、これ、答えたか忘れちゃったから。
Wait a minute, what answer did I write down?
嘘だろ、おい！
No way!
ちょっと、うれしくなかったんじゃないのかよ。
Weren't you happy?
1番嬉しかっ... ああ！
I was happy.
わかりました。
Ah, I see!
書いてないじゃん。
You didn't write it?
まあ、別にふざけたことは書いてないですね。
Well, you didn't write that you messed around or anything.
あ、そうなんだ。
Ah, is that so?
まあ、わかった。
Well, I understand.
真面目に書いてますね。
You wrote it seriously.
まじめ？
Seriously?
どうし、別に何か難しいことは書いてない。
Well, I didn't write anything particularly difficult.
ああ。
Ah, I see.
デビューしてからの1番嬉しかった出来事？
The happiest moment since my debut...
じゃあ、何かが起こったんだ。
So something happened.
なんでしょうね。
What could it be?
起こったの？
Something happened?
起こった？
なんか出来事があった。
Some event happened.
うん。
Yeah.
あった。
There was one?
あった？
まあ、起こった。
Well, it happened.
あ、わかった。
Ah, I got it.
あ、じゃあすばるもわかった。
Oh, Shuba-ru got it too.
そろそろ正解してほしいよな。
It's about time you got the answer right!
そろそろ正解したいな。
I want to get it right soon.
おかゆての仲間としてはそろそろ成功、正解してほしいところですけどね。
As Okayu's peers, we really want you to get it right.
いないよ。
No one.
どうだろね、僕だけかもくんない。
Who knows? Maybe just me.
世界選手権の3人だから！
We are the three top players in the world, you know!
そうだよな。
That's true.
まあね。
Yeah.
そういう褒められ方したわけじゃないんだけど。
I didn't mean to be praised like that!
ころさんもカラフルでいいね！
Korosan's is colorful and nice!
書き終わりました？
Did you finish writing?
では誰から行こうかなあ。
Then who should we start with?
回答オープンしたいと思います！
I'd like to open our answers!
じゃあ ころさん オープン！
Now, Korone-san, open!
すてきなともだちができた
I made wonderful friends.
えっ なにこれ それは
What is that?
せっかくカラフルだったのに 黒のペンで…
Even though it was colorful, with a black pen...
あ、あれよね！ カラーでグラデーションかけて
Ah, right! Putting a color gradation
影みたいにするってことでしょ？
to make it look like shadows, right?
そう、そう。
Yeah, yeah.
なんかすごい分かり合ってる ここふたりが。
These two seem to understand each other so well.
いや、にしてもできただけまっくろやないかい。
But still, it's just completely pitch black once done!
確かに。
True.
やめないよ！
Don't stop me!
やめてあげないよ！
I won't stop you!
では次いきましょうか！
Shall we move on to the next?
はい！
Yes!
じゃあ次はスバルちゃんの回答いきましょうか！
Next, let's look at Subaru-chan's answer!
はい！
Yes!
ではスバルちゃんの回答オープン！
Now, Subaru-chan's answer, open!
みんなと出会えた♡
I met everyone♡
ああ、一緒！ちょっところさんと同じ感じ。
Ah, same! Kind of the same feel as Korone-san.
はじめて一緒です！これは嬉しいなと思いました。
It's the first time we match! I thought that was happy.
どうかな？みおしゃは。
What about you? Mio-sha.
えっ？
Huh?
あ、じゃあみおしゃのまけて
Ah, then Mio-sha's lost...
みおしゃは、しょーだい？だとこうで。
Mio-sha is... probably like this...
でも、ちょっとにてっちゃんにってるかな？
But it's kind of like Nitecchi?
では、みおしゃの回答オープン！
Now, Mio-sha's answer, open!
はい！
Yes!
みんなで一緒に はつもうでに行ったこと
Going to Hatsumode together with everyone.
行ったね！行ったよね！
We went! We went, right!
みおしゃ行ったね！
Mio-sha went!
嬉しいけどね、あの時すごく幸せだって言ってて。
I'm happy, but she said she was so happy back then.
ぼくはね、状況してきて初めて行ったんですよ、初詣に。
You see, I went to Hatsumode for the first time after coming to Tokyo.
それで、いろメンバーの中で誰か大吉出したらみおちゃんち泊まろうって言って、ぼくが大吉出してみんなで泊まったんだよね。すごい幸せだって言ってて。
And we said if anyone in Iroha got Daikichi, we'd stay at Mio-chan's, and I got Daikichi so we all stayed over. She said she was so happy.
あれ？それすばう？
Huh? Is that Subau?
いないよ？
She's not here?
え、みおしゃそれこうでいないよ？
Eh, Mio-sha, you're not like that?
あれ？そう、そう、こうねとすばる？
Huh? Oh, right, Kone and Subaru?
すばうはいないよ。
Subau isn't there.
いやいやいや、まあまあ…
No, no, no, well...
ちょっとおかゆ言うのももういいたくなかった。
I didn't want to say what Okayu was saying anymore.
投げろよ！
Just throw it!
では回答を見ていきましょう！
Now let's look at the answers!
ぼくの答えと回答はこちらです！
My answer and the response are right here!
どうぞ！
Go ahead!
正解：みんなとこうして出会えて超仲良しでいられること
[Correct Answer: Meeting everyone like this and staying super close]
え？ちょっと待って、あれ？ちょっと待って、うちも、うちも、あれ？ちょっと
Eh? Wait a minute, huh? Wait a minute, me too, me too, huh? Wait
スタッフさんの声からころさんとすばるさんが正解という判定です。
From the staff's voice, Korone-san and Subaru-san are judged correct.
え、ぼくたち初詣に行ったんですか？
Eh, did we go to hatsumode?
いやあ、初詣に行って、おかゆは
Well, we went to hatsumode, and Okayu...
幸せだな、初詣に友達と一緒に来て幸せだなあって言ってたんだよね。
said, "I'm so happy, coming to hatsumode with friends makes me so happy."
でもこの「みんな」っていうのはみおちゃんも入ってるみんなだからね。
But this "everyone" includes Mio-chan too, you know.
おかゆー！
Okayu!
はい、ということで2名正解でした。
Yes, so 2 people were correct.
残念だった。
That's too bad.
いいね、正解してきたね。
Nice, you got it right.
なんて言ってもらえるの？
What do you get?
これはスタッフさん1点、行ってんだそうです。1点！1点もらいましたよ。
For this, staff-san says 1 point. 1 point! We got 1 point.
じゃあまだ追いつきそうな感じするな。
Then it feels like we can still catch up.
全然追いつきます。
We can totally catch up.
じゃあ次のクイズ行きましょう！
Now let's go to the next quiz!
問題：大空スバル・大神ミオ・戌神ころね、猫又おかゆが一緒に無人島に行くなら誰？
[Question: Out of Subaru, Mio, Korone, and Okayu, who goes to a deserted island?]
え！？こんなの「一択」だよ！
Eh!? This is the only choice!
一択？こんなの全員が「一択」だろ！一択だろ！
One choice? Everyone would say "one choice" for this! One choice!
一択ですか？これ難しいなー。
One choice? This is difficult.
ちょっと待って、これもうわかっちゃったんだけど、これ。
Wait a minute, I already figured this out.
わかっちゃった。
I figured it out.
何かな？
What could it be?
これは、どうなんだろう？
How about this?
ころさんの…こういうことね、こういうことね！
Korone's... so that's what it means, so that's what it means!
なるほどね、ここにさ…
I see, right here...
デコレーションしてくれんの？
Will you decorate it for me?
お！
Oh!
みんな思いのまま書いてますね。
Everyone is writing as they please.
あ、スバルさん自信がないんですか？
Ah, Subaru-san, are you not confident?
え？
Eh?
ん？
Hmm?
あるよ！
There is!
みおちゃんも書いてますね。
Mio-chan is writing too.
みおちゃんもデコレーションかわいいね。
Mio-chan's decoration is cute too.
かわいいでしょ？
Cute, right?
これはもうさ…
This is already...
これはもうさ、ころさんはね、デコレーションの仕方がね、もう芸術的すぎるのよ。
Korone's way of decorating is just too artistic.
本当に美術館に飾りたいよ。
I really want to display it in an art museum.
飾って！
Display it!
すごい！かわいいでしょ？
Amazing! Cute, right?
その、あれも青紫っぽい色好きだよ。
I also like that bluish-purple color.
イルミネーションみたーい！
It looks like illumination!
ありがとう！
Thank you!
じゃあ、そろそろね、出揃っているので、今回の問題はみんなで一斉にオープンしたいと思います！
Well, everyone's answers are ready, so we'd like everyone to open them all at once!
おーす！
Oos!
じゃあ…
Now...
いいですか？
Are you ready?
はーい！
Yes!
では回答、オープン！
Now, answers, open!
大空スバル！大神ミオ！
Oozora Subaru! Ookami Mio!
えっ、あれ？
Eh, huh?
え、これ謎々じゃないんですか？これ。
Eh, isn't this a riddle? This.
ちょっと待って、そこまで聞いて！落として、落として！
Wait a minute, listen up to there! Drop it, drop it!
おかゆ！
Okayu!
待って！
Wait!
どういうこと？どういうこと？
What do you mean? What do you mean?
何を言ってるんですか？
What are you talking about?
殺人的に勘違いさせた結果ってこと？
You mean the result of making us horribly misunderstand?
だって問題集にさ、書いてあったじゃん最初にさ、
Because it was written in the question book at first,
大空スバル、大神ミオ、戌神ころね、猫又おかゆ、無人島に行くなら誰みたいな書いてあったじゃん。
like "If Oozora Subaru, Ookami Mio, Inugami Korone, and Nekomata Okayu went to a deserted island, who would it be?"
で、
And so,
ここまでが問題ってこと？
Does that mean the whole thing is the question?
それ、これ、あの、無人島に行くのは、ぼくだよ！っていうのかと思ったの。
I thought it meant, "As for who's going to a deserted island, it's me!"
なるほどね！
I see!
あ、そっか！
Ah, I see!
じゃあもう一回問題見せてもらいましょう。
Then let's have them show us the question again.
なぞなぞだぞ！なぞなぞかと思った。
It's a riddle! I thought it was a riddle.
あ、確かに！本筋は、おかゆ、スバル、大神ミオ、犬神ころね、猫又おかゆが、でも誰と一緒に無人島に行くことになっちゃうの？
Ah, true! The main point is Okayu, Subaru, Ookami Mio, Inugami Korone, Nekomata Okayu... wait, who would end up going to a deserted island together?
僕が抜けたら。
If I'm excluded.
確かに！勘違いさせすぎた結果！
True! The result of making us misunderstand too much!
いやでも、わからない、猫又おかゆが一級のものだった場合は、うわあ、それありだわ！それありだわ！
No, but I don't know, if Nekomata Okayu's was top-tier, wow, that makes sense! That makes sense!
でもさ、わかんないじゃん。
But you know, we don't know.
ちょっと、ありえるぞ。答え、いきますよ。答え、ドン！
Wait, that's possible. The answer is coming. The answer is, bam!
正解、大神ミオ！
Correct: Ookami Mio!
やったー！やったー！おかゆと！大神ミオ！
Yay! Yay! With Okayu! Ookami Mio!
ゲームセット！完全に止まった。
Game set! It completely stopped.
こわっ！こわっ！見とるやん！見とるやん！でも聞いて、ミオちゃんさ、食材がないと。
Scary! Scary! You're looking! You're looking! But listen, Mio-chan doesn't have ingredients.
そうだよ！いや、食材を調達してくるわけだから。
That's right! Well, because she'll procure the ingredients.
そう、理由があるわけよ、ちゃんとね。
Right, there's a reason, properly.
なになに？なに？ねえ、いいですか？じゃあ、スバルちゃんからいきますね。
What, what? What? Hey, is that okay? Then Subaru-chan, let's start with you.
回席戻ってください。
Please return to your seats.
まず、スバルちゃんと無人島に行ったのが冬だった場合積みます。
First, if it was winter when you went to a deserted island with Subaru-chan, you're doomed.
それはガチ！スバルちゃんは全く動けなくなってしまうからね。
That's for real! Subaru-chan won't be able to move at all.
動けないのはガチでしょ？ねえ！
Not being able to move is for real, right? Hey!
で、ころさんの場合、無人島が超虫がいっぱいだった場合はもう戦闘不能でしょ？あ、そうか！そうなんだ！確かに。
And, in Koro-san's case, if the deserted island is full of bugs, you're already combat-incapacitated? Ah, is that so! That's right!
で、間をとってミオちゃんは冬でもいけるし、虫は苦手だけど一緒に頑張れるかな？がんばりはするかな？
And taking the middle ground, Mio-chan can go even in winter, and although she dislikes bugs, can she do her best together? She'd probably try her best.
じゃあ頑張るから4人で行こうじゃん。
Then let's all 4 go since she'll try her best.
行かないから！いいじゃん！これ！
We're not going! That's fine! This!
みんなで補い合おうよ！夏だって。
Let's compensate for each other! Even in summer.
夏な！夏な！
Summer! Summer!
まあ、理由がいろいろあるってことね。そうか、バランス型、バランス型。
Well, it means there are various reasons. I see, balanced type, balanced type.
ぼくなりにまあちょっといろいろ考えた結果、ミオちゃんかなっていう感じ。
As a result of me thinking about various things in my own way, I felt it was Mio-chan.
はい。
Yes.
では、次の問題に行きましょうかね。はい、次の問題、どうぞ！
Well then, shall we go to the next question? Yes, next question, go ahead!
猫又おかゆに聞いた、大空スバルの「可愛いと思うところ」はなに？
Asked Nekomata Okayu: What is Oozora Subaru's "cute" point?
おい、え？おい、おめえ。
Hey, eh? Hey, you.
えっと、台本、台本？
Um, script, script?
思うところ？
The point you think is cute?
あ、かわいいとこ。
Ah, the cute point.
でも、おかゆめっちゃ褒めてくれるんだよね。
But Okayu praises me a lot, you know.
え、ちょっと、ちなみにどういうところ褒められたかちょっと、言ってみてよ。
Eh, wait, by the way, try telling us what kind of things she praised you for.
おかゆ、なんでも褒めてくれるよ。
Okayu praises me for anything.
え？そうなの？全肯定ってこと？
Eh? Is that so? You mean total affirmation?
なにか、なにか、な？
Something, something, huh?
え、どこっててもなんかね、すごいフェチズムの高いところとか褒めてくれる。
Eh, wherever it is, like, she praises things with really high fetishism.
え？そうなの？お尻柔らかくていいよねとかってこと？
Eh? Is that so? Like "Your butt is soft and nice"?
それは聞いたことないです。
I've never heard that.
それは聞いた...お尻柔らかくていいよね、それがかわいいところだ。
I've never heard... "Your butt is soft and nice", that's the cute point.
で、でもね、なんだっけな？なんか、言ってんだよな。なんだろ、なにかな。
B-But, what was it? She was saying something. I wonder what, what could it be.
なにかな。お尻柔らかいの？
What could it be? Is it about your soft butt?
これなんか、自分でさ、かわいいと思うところ発表するみたいで嫌なんだけど。
This is like, having to announce what I think is cute about myself, and I hate it.
でもね、当てに行きたくない ですか？
But hey, don't you want to go try guessing?
当てたい！
I want to guess!
そうですよ。
That's right.
なんだんだ。
What is it, what is it.
なにかな。かわいいところ。ペチッてて言ってたっけな。なにかな。考えてるね。めっちゃ考えてる。自分は難しいかもね。
What could it be? The cute point. Did she say something about 'peti'? What could it be. She's thinking. She's thinking hard. For herself, maybe it's difficult.
まあ、確かにね。
Well, true.
なんか、スバルちゃんは、こういうところが言いところだよねってよく...なんだっけな！思い出して、思い出して！
Like, Subaru-chan, this kind of point is a good point, she often... What was it! Remember, remember!
思い出してくださいね。
Please remember.
お、なかなか筆が進んでないですね。スバルちゃん。
Oh, your writing isn't progressing much, is it, Subaru-chan?
自分のことなのに！うーん。
Even though it's about yourself! Hmm.
あ、ミオちゃんは、かけました！書き終わってますね。
Ah, Mio-chan has written it! She's already finished writing.
いや、これでしょう。たぶん。
Well, it must be this. Probably.
えがかわいい？
Her smile is cute?
うん。
Yeah.
あ、なるほどね。
Ah, I see.
顔が？
Her face is?
はいはいはい。ころさんも書き終わってますね。はいはい。あ、なるほどなるほど。
Right, right, right. Korone-san has also finished writing. Yes, yes. Ah, I see, I see.
では、今回はころさんからオープンしていきたいと思います。
Well then, this time we'll open from Koro-san.
あ、待って、帽子書いていい？
Ah, wait, can I draw a hat?
あ、スバルは帽子書こう。
Ah, Subaru, draw a hat.
あ、いい、いい。みんなイラスト書いとるやん。
Ah, good, good. Everyone's drawing illustrations.
イラスト描いてるみんな。
Everyone's drawing illustrations.
はい、ではいきたいと思います！
Alright, then let's go!
では、ころさんからオープン！
Now, opening from Koro-san!
パン！
Bam!
下を向かないから / はにかむとき？
Doesn't look down / When she acts shy?
下をむきながら はにかむしぐさ？
Looking down and acting shy?
すごい細かい！ すごい細かいぞ
That's so specific! That's way too specific!
そんなことしたっけ？
Did I do that?
そんなことしてるじゃん
You totally do!
なんか、スバルちゃんがワンピ着て
Like, Subaru-chan wore a one-piece dress,
ワンピ着て、ちょっとやってみて
wore a one-piece, and tried doing this—
そのワンピ、超かわいいじゃんに合ってるじゃん、めっっちゃかわいいじゃんって
Like, "That one-piece looks so cute on you, it suits you, it's super cute!"
うんうんうん、ちょっとやってみて
Yeah, yeah, yeah. "Try doing it a bit."
えっ？あっ、えっ？ありがとう……みたいないう。ありがとう！
"Eh? Ah, eh? Thank you..." something like that. "Thank you!"
えっ、かわいい！
Eh, so cute!
そんなことしたっけコロネの前で？
Did you really do that in front of Korone?
ちょっと恥ずかしがって誇張してますね
You're exaggerating because you're embarrassed, right?
ああ、なるほどね！おい、誇張してるじゃんか！
Ah, I see! Hey, you're exaggerating!
では次はみおちゃんいきましょうか！はい、お願いします。
Now let's go with Mio-chan! Yes, please.
ごはんをたべるとねむくなっちゃうところ、スキャッ
"When you eat a meal, you get sleepy, sca—"
血統の違いが
"The difference in bloodlines—"
いや、何にしても言うよ。めちゃくちゃ眠くなっちゃう、すぐ。
Well, you'd say that for anything. You get sleepy right away.
確かにね！野菜からね、野菜から食べましょうね。
True! Eat your veggies first, okay?
じゃあ最後いきますか？ではスバルちゃん、自分が思うかわいいところをおねがいします！
Shall we do the last one? Then Subaru-chan, please give us the cute trait you think you have!
すなおなところ！
"An honest personality!"
これは何このボタン？ これは帽子？おい、帽子だわ！おい！
What's with this button? Is this a hat? Hey, it's a hat! Hey!
ボタン！ボタンかと思った！
A button! I thought it was a button!
これ、まあ、不条理されたら全部おもしろいて思うし、みんなのそういうところ
If it gets subverted, it's hilarious, and everyone has that kind of...
言われてみれば確かに。あれ？あれ？なんかちょっと違うんか？
When you mention it, true. Huh? Huh? Is it a bit different?
プレゼントもらったときにでっかい声で“え～～～！うれしい～～～！”って言うところ
"When you receive a present, saying in a huge voice, 'Ehhhh! So happyyyyy!'"
言うよ、言うよ！言うよ言うよ！あらあらあら！
I say that! I totally say that! Oh my, oh my!
だってうれしいんだもん！
Because I'm so happy!
でももらったプレゼントめちゃ楽しみにしてるよ！
But you're super excited about the presents you receive!
ある意味正解なので、ポイントを与えるということです！
In a sense it's correct, so we're giving you points!
やったー！おめでとうございます！すなおなんでね。あ、これもよろしくお願いします！おめでとうございます！
Yay! Congratulations! Because you're honest. Ah, please take care of this too! Congratulations!
では次の問題どうぞ！猫又おかゆに聞いた、大神ミオの「PON」だと思うところはなに？
Now for the next question! What did Nekomata Okayu think is Ookami Mio's "PON" moment?
え、それ場面？まあ、PONだと思うところ、日常的にみたいな感じかな。
Eh, like a situation? Well, a "PON" moment, like in daily life or something.
え、ちょっと待って、そんなおかゆの前でそんな当時だって……どっちかっていうと僕の方がPONしまくってるからね！
Eh, wait a minute, in front of Okayu back then... if anything, I'm the one making all the PON mistakes!
トイレから出てきたらスカートが全部パンツの中に入ってたり
Like coming out of the bathroom with your skirt completely tucked into your underwear—
それそれそれじゃん！だってミオシャとおかゆが、カボチャパンツみたいになってたとき
Exactly that! Because Mio-sha and Okayu looked like they were wearing pumpkin pants—
ミオちゃん「お待たせ！」って言って出てきたらね、なんかほとんど入ってるっていうか、全部パンツだから！
Mio-chan said, "Sorry to keep you waiting!" and came out, and it was mostly inside, or rather, it was all underwear!
いやなんでそれでかき消されちゃうよ！だって、私のPONだからね！
Hey, why does that cancel it out! That's my PON moment, you know!
そっか。これはミオちゃんをPONと思う僕の……PONなところか。
I see. This is my... "PON" moment of thinking Mio-chan is PON.
手遅れだよ、ミオしゃ！うちのPONなところ？なんですかね……
It's too late, Mio-sha! My PON moment? I wonder what it is...
マジで思いつかん。一応私も答え見とこ。
I seriously can't think of any. I'll check the answer just in case.
PONなところですよ。まあ、ミオちゃんはいつもね、僕たちのこと引っ張ってくれる存在だから
A PON moment. Well, Mio-chan is always the one leading us,
こう、ピンとは来ないよね。来ないよね。僕もかなり悩みました。
so it doesn't really click, right? It doesn't. I struggled quite a bit too.
ミオちゃんのPONなところかって。わからないけど、リスナーの皆さんもどうですか？
"Mio-chan's PON moment?" I didn't know, but what about you listeners?
えー、ちょっと見てみましょうか。えー！？そんな思いつくみんな？
Uh, let's take a look. Ehh!? You guys can think of that many?
なるほど、なるほど。リスナーの皆さんは、
I see, I see. As for the listeners,
え、この間ペコラと刺身についている菊の花が食べれると知らなかったみたいな、そんなこと書いてありましたね。
uh, it was written that recently you didn't know you could eat the chrysanthemum flower on sashimi with Pekora.
ああ、こないだ！刺身についてるやつをタンポポだと思ってずっと信じてたのに、あれは菊の花だということを知りました。
Ah, recently! I honestly believed the thing on sashimi was a dandelion all this time, but I found out it was a chrysanthemum.
おタンポポ事件！おタンポポ事件。おタンポポ。確かに「おタンポポ」って言ってた！おタンポポ事件。さあ、どうですか皆さん？書き終わりました？
The dandelion incident! The dandelion incident. Dandelion. You definitely said "dandelion"! The dandelion incident. Now, how about everyone? Are you done writing?
まあ、僕もね、めちゃ迷って書きましたから、
Well, I was pretty lost too.
どうかな、どうかなー？
Let's see.
いいですか？そろそろじゃあ、いっちゃいますよ。
Alright, are you ready? Time to reveal!
まだないよ！ まだない！
Not yet! Not yet!
いっせーのおーで開いていきましょう。
On the count of three, let's open them up.
では、回答オープン！
Now, answers, reveal!
え！？ なにそれ！？
Wait, what is that?
待って待って！ それはころねだから！
Wait, wait, that's Korone!
ちがう、ちがう、なんか、もうちょっとさ、あの、
Wait, wait, I felt like...
なんか、あの、ささやかな回を。
You know, mundane stuff.
そんな時あったか！？
When would that ever happen?!
だってみおさんいつもしっかりしてるじゃん！
Mio-san is always so put-together, you know?
あ、そう、ですね。
Yeah, that's true.
思いつかなかったから！
I just couldn't think of anything else!
大神みおはカラーつけてるのかなって思ったの！
So you thought she puts hair rollers on?
先輩これわ！突っ込み！
That's way too savage!
なるほどね！
I see, I see.
みおちゃんは頭にカラーをつけてきてね。
Mio-san with hair rollers on, huh.
じゃあみおちゃんいこうか。
Alright, let's look at Mio-san's.
よく言い間違いをするところ！
"Making flubs a lot."
たまにね、ちょっとやっちゃうみたいなね。
Yeah, she tends to do that a lot, huh.
なるほどね。
True, true.
まあ、よくあるポンですね。
Well, that's a classic "PON" moment.
そうですね。
Totally.
じゃあスバルちゃんは？
What about Subaru-chan?
そうめんとかを突然やりだす。
"Suddenly starting somen noodles or ASMR."
え、これもポんなん？
Is that a "PON" too?!
普段しっかりしたステから！
Since she usually eats healthy!
こういうことやるんだ！みたいな。
Like, "She's actually into this stuff?!"
意外性ってこと？
So it was unexpected?
ちょっとポンかわいいっていうことで。
Just that "PON" equals cute.
ポンかわいいってことみおちゃん。
So "PON" is cute, according to Mio-san.
なるほどね。
I see.
そういうことなのか、それ。
So that's what it was.
では、正解見ていきましょう。どん！
Alright, let's check the correct answer. Bam!
思い浮かばないので想像で答えます。
"I couldn't think of anything, so I guessed!"
たまにピン止めをたくあんと間違えて食べている。
"Sometimes I mistake hairpins for pickled daikon and eat them."
当たるかこんな！
Nailed it!
いやだって食べちゃうよ！
Wait, I'd totally eat one!
いやだてもう思い浮かばないって書いたらさ、
Well, you wrote "I couldn't think of anything"...
正解してたわけじゃん！
that means you got it right, right?!
たしかに！ たしかに！
True! Exactly!
それ言ってたじゃん！
You even said that before!
思い浮かばないよね。
You couldn't think of anything, right?
え、でも頭のカラーを食べるって書いてたら正解だったってこと？
Wait, if you wrote "Eating hair rollers," would that be correct?
それ捏造！
Well, that's fabrication!
でもね、ねつ造してるって意味では近いのよね。
Well, in the sense of fabricating normal people's "PON"...
捏造、普通の人間のポンを。
Fabricating normal people's "PON"?!
なんかお腹空いたなーもう。
Wait, I'm getting hungry.
あ、あるよ！
Oh, there are some!
あれ？あ、これたくあんじゃなかったわ。
Wait, this isn't pickled daikon!
ってこと？
Seriously?
いや、すっごい空気になっちゃう、そんなこと言ったら。
That would be way too airheaded!
ごめんね、滑らせちゃって。
Sorry, I slipped up!
いや突っ込めるよ、そんなこと！
It's even funnier when you say it!
いや、みおちゃんがやってると、なおさら突っ込めないよ！
If Mio-san does it, it's even funnier!
確かにね。
True, true!
スバルちゃんがもう割って入って突っ込んでいかないと。
Subaru-chan would just barge in and roast her!
それ違いますよ！って言わないと。
Like, "That's wrong!"
みおちゃんかわいいとかないな。
Mio-san wouldn't say "Cute" or anything.
やってないから。
She wouldn't!
これ本当のうちじゃないから、想像だからこれ。
Because this isn't the real Uchi, it's just imagination!
ということで、えー、正解者はナシと！
So, the winner is... Nash!
いうことで次が最後の、次が最後の問題です。
Now for the final question.
いいですか？問題どうぞ！
Alright, let's go with the final question!
猫又おかゆに聞いた、戌神ころねの「尊敬できるところ」はなに？
"I asked Nekomata Okayu: What is Inugami Korone's most respectable trait?"
これ言ってた！
Oh, she said it!
言ってた？
Did she?
これ言ってた！
She said it!
え、言ってた？
Did she really?
なんだろ、なんだろな。
Hmm, I wonder what it is.
なんかしか思い浮かばないんだけど。
I can't think of anything!
なんだろー？
What could it be?
あ、これはわかる！
Oh, I know this!
スバルちゃん筆が進んでおります。
Subaru-chan's pen is moving right along!
書き進めております。
Mio-san is writing hers down too.
これしか思い浮かばないんだけど。
I can't think of anything!
待って、私もなんて書いたっけな。
Wait, what did I write down?
でも確かに。
But honestly...
ねえ。
Right?
これ、これしか思いつかん。
That's all I could think of!
え、笑って るってことは。
Wait, you're laughing?
いや待って、でも私なんて書いたか忘れちゃったよ。
Wait, what did I write? I forgot!
あ、そっか、そうなんだ。
Ah, right, right, right.
えーと、これ、あ、今スタッフさんから、
Oh, staff-san says...
これ最後の問題なんで、
since this is the final question,
1億点だそうですよ。
it's worth 100,000 points!
ええー！？
What?!
まじか！
Seriously?!
勝ちだ！
We win!
勝ち！
え、みんなが、嘘でしょ！ これ違うって言われたら、
If everyone says "That's wrong,"
全部言ってたよって。
well, I already said it!
だから、そのうちの1つだからね。
But hey, it's one of those things.
今回特質して1つ選んでるわけだから。
We specially picked one out.
そっか。
Oh, I see.
どうかなー？
So, which one?
え、じゃあこれかな？
Could it be this one?
なにかしらー？なにかしらの、のこ、の、のこ、の、
What could it be? Korone, Korone...
のこ、の、のこ、の、のこ、の、
Korone, Korone, Korone...
なにかしら、なにかの、なにかの、のこ、のこ、のこ、のこ、のこ、のこ、
What is it? Korone, Korone...
のこ、のこ、のこ、の、のこ、の、のこ、のこ、のこ、のこ、のこ、のこ！
Korone, Korone, Korone...
え、これ一個だけなの？
Wait, is there only one?
一つだけとりあえず選んで書きましたよ。
Well, I just picked one for now.
あ、でもみんな書き終わってるから。
Well, everyone's done writing anyway.
これでいきましょうか、スバルちゃん。
Let's just go with this, Subaru-chan.
誰からいこうかなー？
Alright, who should we start with?
じゃあ、今回も一斉に。
Alright, let's all reveal at once.
どん！
Bam!
お！ お！
Oh! Oh!
どうぞ、読んでくざさい。
Go ahead, read it!
何においてもう天才！
"No matter what, a genius!"
え、嬉しい。おー。
"Oh, I'm so happy. Wow."
え？みんな行くの早くない？
"Huh? Aren't you all going too fast?"
え？みんなみんな何でそんな
"Huh? Why is everyone like--"
え？みんな次々行くの早すぎん？
"Everyone's going one after another way too fast!"
次は誰、誰から？ はい。
"Next is who, who's going? Yes."
どんなに怒っても最後は許しちゃうところ。
"No matter how angry they get, in the end they always forgive you."
あー、お母さんぽくていいよね。
"Ah, it's very motherly, nice."
そうだね。
"That's right."
パス子に？
"To Pasuko?"
で、最後
"And, finally..."
最後は？
"Finally?"
水まわりのおそうじを毎日してるとこ
"Cleaning the water areas every day."
え！すごい！それそう！それそう！
"Eh! Amazing! That's it! That's it!"
でもマジでさ、これそれそう！
"But seriously, this is totally it!"
おかゆから聞いたことあるこの話。
"I've heard this story from Okayu before."
え、うそ！おかゆが正解かもしれないって
"Eh, no way! Saying Okayu might be correct..."
ころさんは毎日掃除してるからすごいよねって
"Korone-san cleans every day, so she's amazing."
ってちょっと気を使ってさ
"trying to be polite..."
ああ、なるほどな。
"Ah, I see."
ということでじゃあ行きますよ。
"With that, let's go."
はい。
"Yes."
はい、お願いします。
"Yes, please."
ドン！ダダーン！
"Bam! Da-da-da-dum!"
遊びに行くと絶対絶対絶対絶対絶対絶対絶対手がきれい
"When you go to visit, your hands are absolute- absolutely- absolutely clean!"
ということでころさん正解！
"With that, Korone-san is correct!"
やばい！
"No way!"
おい、ちょっと待て、おい。それは違うだろ。
"Hey, wait a minute, hey. That's wrong, right?"
で、でききて壁から。おい、それはダメだぞ。それもよく言ってるじゃん。
"You can come out from the wall. Hey, that's no good. You always say that too."
それでも幅広すぎる。それも言ってるけど、今回選んだのはこれっていうね。
"That's still too broad. You say that too, but the one chosen this time is this."
なるほどね！
"I see!"
はい、ということで不正解よ！いえーい！
"Well then, incorrect! Yay!"
えっ、じゃあ今のが1億円ってこと？
"Eh, so that means the current one was 100 million yen?"
そうですよ、1億円。
"That's right, 100 million yen."
あ、では、結果発表の前に、
"Ah, well, before the results announcement,"
えっと、一曲聴いてもらうみたいですよ。
"it seems you'll listen to a song."
え？なにがなに？ねこまたおかゆで、もぐもぐYUMMY！
"Eh? What what? Nekomata Okayu with Mogu Mogu YUMMY!"
森羅万象の悪戦苦闘も
Even the struggles of all creation
マヨネーズかけたら大体美味しくなる
usually taste delicious if you add mayonnaise!
君が泣いてもお腹は空くよ
Even if you cry, your stomach still gets empty,
消化できなかったごめんなさい。
"I'm sorry" that couldn't be digested.
酸いも甘いも勝手に食べて
Eating whatever sour or sweet things as you please,
ご迷惑おかけしています
causing you trouble.
パクチーな茎 変な味のジュース
Cilantro stems, juice with a weird taste,
心を無にして飲みこみます
I swallow them with a blank mind.
ああ 混沌 情報過多のレストランで
Ah, in a restaurant overflowing with chaotic information,
嘘っぱちのメニューにお茶こぼして
spilling tea on a phony menu,
君ともぐもぐもぐもぐもぐ
munching away with you, munch-munch-munch-munch!
銃撃戦の真ん中でもぐもぐ
Munching right in the middle of a firefight,
魑魅魍魎ハラペコの間の違い
mistaking ghouls for a hungry stomach,
満腹になる未来を願っているよ
wishing for a future where we're full.
もぐもぐもぐもぐもぐ 世界が終わる前に
Munch-munch-munch-munch-munch, before the world ends,
もぐもぐやみい まじかみい
Mogu-mogu yummy, maji-kamii!
やむやむ ありのまま
Yamu-yamu, just as we are,
もぐもぐやみい まじかみい
Mogu-mogu yummy, maji-kamii!
この世を味わうんだ うまうま
Tasting this world, uma-uma!
理論武装のミルフィーユサンド
A mille-feuille sandwich of armed theory,
特盛り希望のオーロラソース
aurora sauce with a request for extra-large portions.
大雑把な味付け お目に見えてよ
Rough seasoning, show it to my eyes!
美味しくなったらオッケーオッケー
If it becomes delicious, it's okay, okay!
芋も類もいっぱい食べて
Eating plenty of potatoes and root veggies,
汚れた足元ぬぐいます
wiping our dirty feet.
おにぎり定食 過去のフルコース
Onigiri set meal, a full course of the past,
罠を疑い気を付けます
suspecting traps and being careful.
探索流刑 秘境のバイキングで
In an unexplored Viking buffet of search exile,
特選品と絶品料理より分けて
separating the choice items from exquisite dishes,
君ともぐもぐもぐもぐもぐ
munching away with you, munch-munch-munch-munch!
珍味も両手で好むれ
Welcoming delicacies with both hands,
仲のいい君と息残れたら
if I can survive together with you, good friends,
いいなもぐもぐもぐもぐもぐ
wouldn't it be nice, munch-munch-munch-munch!
もぐもぐやみい まじかみい
Mogu-mogu yummy, maji-kamii!
今夜の晩ごはんは
Tonight's dinner is...
もぐもぐやみい まじかみい
Mogu-mogu yummy, maji-kamii!
次はお前の番だ
Next is your turn!
もぐもぐやみい まじかみい
Mogu-mogu yummy, maji-kamii!
やむやむ ありのまま
Yamu-yamu, just as we are,
もぐもぐやみい まじかみい
Mogu-mogu yummy, maji-kamii!
この世を味わうんだ うまうま
Tasting this world, uma-uma!
もぐもぐもぐもぐもぐもぐもぐもぐもぐもぐもぐもぐもぐもぐもぐもぐ
Munch-munch-munch-munch-munch-munch-munch-munch...
もぐもぐやみい もぐもぐもぐもぐもぐもぐもぐもぐもぐもぐもぐもぐもぐもぐもぐもぐ
Mogu-mogu yummy, mogu-mogu-mogu...
もぐもぐやみい
Mogu-mogu yummy!
結果発表～！
Results announcement~!
結果発表……一体誰が一番なんだいったい！
Results... Who on earth is number one?!
結果発表～！
Results announcement~!
それでは注目の結果発表です！
Now, for the highly anticipated results!
あ、猫又おかゆのことを最も理解しているのは誰なのか！
Ah, who understands Nekomata Okayu the best?!
全員の得点、オープン！
Everyone's scores, open!
うおー！
Whoa!
バグってるって！ころねのバグってるってこれ！
It's bugged! Korone's score is totally bugged!
おかしいだろ、桁違いのやつが。
That's weird, it's on a completely different scale.
なんだろう、これ何なんだこれは！
What is this, what on earth is this?!
まぁちょっとね、スバルちゃんとミオちゃんは2点と1点というちょっとかすみたいな……
Well, Subaru-chan and Mio-chan have 2 points and 1 point, kind of like scraps...
世界大会突破してんだよ！大体正常なんだ、こいつら！
We passed the World Tournament! This is totally normal for us!
負け犬の遠吠えは聞こえないということで次まいります。
Losers' barking can't be heard, so let's move on.
はい、えー優勝した犬神ころねさんには、えー、番組特製、
Yes, um, for the winner Inugami Korone-san, um,
猫又おかゆがもっと好きになるドリンクを飲んでいただきます！
you will drink a drink that makes you love Nekomata Okayu even more!
う、うそ！飲むの！？優勝特典がそれなの！？
Wh-What?! You drink it?! That's the winning prize?!
いいの？もっと好きになっちゃうじゃん！以外だが以外。
Is that okay? You'll love her even more! That's unexpected.
なんでミオちゃんとスバルちゃんに飲んでもらいますか？
Why don't we have Mio-chan and Subaru-chan drink it?
ちょっと待って、さっきと言っていることなんか、あ、気持ち悪くなってきた。
Wait a minute, what you said earlier... Ah, I'm starting to feel sick.
ミオちゃん何で？ちょっと待って！優勝者は飲んで！
Mio-chan, why? Wait a minute! The winner drinks it!
じゃあさ、タフさん、ドリンクの準備をしてもらっていいですか？
Well then, Tofu-san, could you prepare the drinks?
ええー！いやおかしくしないだけどん！
Ehh?! No, don't make it weird!
コロさんさ、十分僕のこと好きだから飲まなくていいよ。
Koro-san, you already love me enough so you don't have to drink it.
よかった！よかった！
Thank goodness! Thank goodness!
じゃあ、おいちら！
Well then, you guys!
ドリンク準備されたということで、わあ！だれか手に持って！色やば！
The drinks have been prepared, Whoa! Someone hold it! The color is crazy!
なんだこれ！？色やばすぎでしょ！
What is this?! The color is way too crazy!
なんかすごいやばい！やめてよ！うちも持ってるのノルマだノルマこれ！
It looks super dangerous! Stop it! Holding it is a quota for us too!
でもね、おいしそう！おいしそうじゃねえか。
But you know, it looks delicious! Doesn't it look delicious?
なんかさ、ライムみたいなさ、そうそうそう。じゃあ、早速飲んでください！
It's kind of like lime, yeah. Well then, please drink up right away!
じゃあスバルがのまーして、スバルがミオちゃんののませるから。え、急になんかミオちゃん！？かけちまうかもしれない。
Then Subaru will make her drink, and Subaru will make Mio-chan drink. Eh, suddenly something, Mio-chan?! I might splash it.
はげ！やめろやめろ！どうですか？
Hey! Stop it, stop it! How is it?
美味しいですか？どう？どんな味？
Is it delicious? How is it? What does it taste like?
え、でも悪くないぞ。あ、でもなんかスッキリしてて美味しいかも！
Eh, but it's not bad. Ah, but it feels refreshing and maybe delicious!
美味しい！美味しい！すごい、なんかドリンクどうしてくれる。
Delicious! Delicious! Amazing, what are you going to do with the drink?
え、マジいいのかと思って飲みたかった！
Eh, I thought it was seriously fine so I wanted to drink it!
スムージーみたいな感じか。
It feels like a smoothie.
でもこれで僕のことを大好きになれるなら、めちゃめちゃいいですよね。
But if this can make you love me even more, that's really great, right?
確かに、おてがるかもしれない。おてがる。
True, it might be easy. Easy.
じゃあ、ころさんにも飲んでもらいますか。
Well then, shall we have Koro-san drink it too?
おてがる、おてがる！いいの？
Easy, easy! Is that okay?
これにもね、特製ジュース。美味しいからこれ。
This also has special juice. Because it's delicious.
直で！？直でするの！？
Directly?! You're doing it directly?!
美味しい？
Is it delicious?
美味しい！
Delicious!
美味しい！美味しい！美味しい！良かった！
Delicious! Delicious! Delicious! I'm glad!
ということで、以上！猫又おかゆわかり手グランプリでした！
And with that, that's it! It was Nekomata Okayu's "Wakariate Grand Prix"!
ころね！ころね！
Korone! Korone!
グレチ！
Grati!
君が抱えてる 心の傷口に
Into the wounds of your heart that you hold,
優しいふりの嘘を すり込んでく 互いも切ずに
I rub in kind-sounding lies without even cutting each other.
消せぬとも知らずに 寄り添うことが 君の生きがい
Without knowing they cannot be erased, drawing close is your reason for living,
ずるり とろり 引きずり込んで 戻れないそこへ落としてあげる
slipping, melting, dragging you down, letting you fall to a place of no return.
いつか 君が 僕だけ求めて 泣く姿を見て
Someday, seeing you cry, seeking only me,
見たい 君が望むなら 僕は王子さま
I want to see it. If you wish for it, I am your prince.
目覚めのキスなら 毒入りの愛で 魂てあげるよ
If it's a waking kiss, I will imbue your soul with poisoned love
楽になれるなら 嘘は毒にも薬にもなる だから 悪くはないでしょ
If it brings relief, lies become both poison and medicine, so it can't be bad, right?
涙で歪める 虚ろな関係も
Tears warping even this hollow relationship,
僕はきつく嘘で脱ぎ合わせる
I tightly match and strip away with lies.
気づかなくていい 本当のことなんて
No need to notice what the real truth is.
知らない嘘はないのと同じ
An unknown lie is the same as none.
するり とろり 飲みやすいように
Smoothly, thickly, so it's easy to drink,
甘くとかした 薬みたいだ
like a sweetly melted medicine.
まるでお菓子のように見せかけて
Making it look just like sweets,
君に口移す 契約僕との夜だけ
passing it mouth-to-mouth on our night alone.
君はお姫様 烏の靴穿き
You are a princess wearing crow's shoes,
死ぬまでダンスを愛してあげるよ
I'll love dancing with you until you die.
苦しまないように 嘘は何より
So you won't suffer, lies more than anything
君を救える 誰が僕を咎めるの？
can save you. Who is blaming me?
平穏 正しい真実の方が よほど残酷な毒になるでしょ
Peace and correct truth will become far more cruel poison.
午前零時 眠れないほどに
At midnight, unable to even sleep,
生きることに怯えてる
frightened of living.
僕はどちら 君が望むなら
Which am I? If you wish for it,
僕は王子様 目覚めのキスなら
I am a prince. If it's a waking kiss,
毒入りの愛で 演じてあげるよ
I'll play it out with poison-laced love.
魔法が溶けるまで 僕はどこでも
Until the magic fades, wherever I am,
薬でもいい それも悪くない
even medicine is fine, that's not so bad either.
嘘つきな 独の王子様
A lying prince of poison,
夢を語らずに 鬱を語るけれど
not speaking of dreams, but speaking of depression,
僕だけに君は笑う
you smile only at me.
それだけは嘘じゃない真実
That alone is not a lie, it's the truth.
だから 悪くはないでしょう
So, it's not bad, isn't it?
それですいいよ
That's fine.
いっそ塵になって 転がっていたいけど
I'd rather become dust and roll around, but
みっともないから 口から出る「大丈夫」
since it's unseemly, a "Don't worry" slips out.
透明な街をすり抜け 傷痕晒したまま
Slipping through the transparent town, leaving scars exposed,
耳障りメトロのメロディー こんな僕も肯定して
ear-offending metro melody, affirm even a me like this.
感情も 心臓も 値段がつくらしいね
Emotions and hearts seem to come with a price tag.
エンドレスな 新規リスナー いくらですか
Endless new listeners, how much are you?
幸せとは かみさま
What is happiness, God?
ウザったい 恥を捨てたら
If you throw away annoying embarrassment,
並べた嘘にキスしよう i love u
let's kiss the lined-up lies, I love you.
最底辺の楽園さ 孤独と指絡ませ アデュー、サロー
It's a bottom-feeders' paradise, intertwining fingers with loneliness, adieu, salope.
何者でもない僕を せめて慰めてよ アデュー、サロー
At least comfort me, who am nobody, adieu, salope.
簡単なことも出来ずに 息を止めて歩いた
Walking while holding my breath, unable to do even simple things.
愛くるしいあの子は いつの間にか笑えなくなっちゃった
That adorable girl somehow stopped being able to smile.
まだいてんだこの人生は 曇り模様 晴れ間探し
This life is still dragging on, searching for a break in the cloudy weather.
強がっているわけじゃない 誰か僕を見てよ
It's not that I'm putting up a front, someone look at me.
見つけて
Find me.
ウザったい 恥を捨てたら
If you throw away annoying embarrassment,
並べた嘘にキスしよう i love u
let's kiss the lined-up lies, I love you.
承認に飢えた亡霊さ 負け惜しみで叫んだ アデュー、サロー
A ghost starved for validation, shouting out of spite, adieu, salope.
何者でもない僕を 慰める奴はいない アデュー、サロー
There's no one to comfort me, a nobody, adieu, salope.
はい、ということで
Hi, so...
え、改めてましてここまで聴いてくださった皆さん、ね、猫又おかゆですよ〜！
Um, to everyone who listened up to this point once again,
I'm Nekomata Okayu~!
え、阿修羅草子聴いてくださってありがとうございます。
Um, thank you so much for listening to "Ashura Soushi."
やっぱね、阿修羅草子は、こう、って電話が来るとこ、やっぱみんな大好きだと思うんで
You know, with "Ashura Soushi," when that phone rings,
I think everyone loves that part,
ちょっとね、電話のセリフを言うのがちょっと一番のヤマ場というかさ、こう一番ドキドキしながら歌うというか、喋るところだなといつも思っております。
so saying the phone line is kind of the biggest climax,
singing or rather speaking it while feeling the most nervous.
はい、ということでですね、あの、今までオリジナル曲たくさん歌わせていただいたんですが、
Hi, so, um, up until now I've sung
a lot of original songs, but
ここからですね、なんと、まだ未発表のオリジナル曲の発表となります！
from here, amazingly, it'll be the announcement
of a brand new, unreleased original song!
ええ、いいですか？発表しちゃって、いいですかぁ？
Um, is that okay? Can I announce it?
Is it really okay?
では、えーっとる、るるるるるるるる...はい、ターン！
Now, um... (humming)... and, ta-da!
えー、今回新しく歌わせていただきます、毒杯スロウ！おおー！
Um, the new song I'll be singing this time
is "Dokuhai Swallow"! Whoa!
まってまって、まってまだ喋りたいことあるから
Wait, wait, wait, I still have things
I want to talk about!
あの、こちらの楽曲は、えー、僕も歌ってみたで歌わせていただいている、失楽ペトリという楽曲を作っているナナホシ管弦楽団さんに書き下ろししていただきました！
Um, this song was newly written for me by Nanahoshi Kanzakidan,
who also created "Shitsuraku Petri," which I've covered.
じゃあ、あの照明係さん、今から歌いますんで、えー電気消してもらっていいですよ。
So, um, lighting staff, I'm going to sing now,
so you can turn off the lights.
では、聴いてください、毒杯スロウ！
Now, please listen, "Dokuhai Swallow"!
謳えた業に乗せ
Riding on the sinful karma we sang of,
ひっそりと爪を研いでいる
I quietly sharpen my claws.
煙さえ我が物に 香り纏わせお前のようにな
Claiming even the smoke as my own, draping it in fragrance like you.
この身体のどこかに 生まれ持っていたなら
If I was born with it somewhere in this body,
何者にも食えぬ 毒 毒 毒
something that nothing could devour—poison, poison, poison!
如何様な美味さと
No matter how delicious it may smell,
喉から手が出るほど 毒 毒 毒
to the point of making my mouth water—poison, poison, poison!
ああ 賀すに賀すにと 構えていた諸刃の剣
Ah, bracing with double-edged swords to congratulate,
切っ先立って じっといられるのなら
if you can stand still with the blade pointed—
望むがいい スロウ スロウ
then wish for it, slow, slow.
その嘴で 深く患った病を 求め咽ぶ
With that beak, sobbing and yearning for the deeply afflicted illness.
願うまま棘を着こませればと
Hoping to make it wear thorns as desired,
いがらっぽい喉を鳴らす
I rattle my scratchy throat.
何食わぬ貌にさえ こっそり牙を宿していたい
Even with an unbitten look, I want to secretly harbor fangs.
成り果てぬ顔にさえ こっそり牙を宿していたい
Even with a face that hasn't fallen apart,
I want to secretly harbor fangs.
齧り尽くしたいだけで
Just wanting to gnaw it all away,
吠えてはみてもお前のようにわ
even if I howl and bare my teeth like you,
そのカイナのいずこに 隠し持っていたのか
where in those arms did you conceal it all along?
はらわたを溶かす 毒 毒 毒
Melting your entrails—poison, poison, poison!
足様に暴そうと 傍立てれもしよが
No matter how you try to rage and stand by your feet,
生唾垂るたるほど 毒 毒 毒
to the point of drooling fresh saliva—poison, poison, poison!
ああ 芽生に芽生にと 築んできた甘ったるの
Ah, building up sweet things as they sprout,
端末に出して 咽頭渡せるのなら
if you can push it to the terminals and hand over the throat—
好むがいい スロウ スロウ
then prefer it, slow, slow.
その掲げてわ 引く抜け破れどレイの
Holding that up, tearing and ripping through the phantom's
下で転がす 背をまもんの老いごと羽ばたければと
rolling beneath, as if fluttering with the old phantom's back...
指を加え見ているか
are you just watching with your fingers in your mouth?
今日も今日とて 口元に朱を塗りたくる ああ
Today, as always, smearing crimson over my lips, ah—
スロウ スロウ まだ耳元で
Slow, slow, still right in my ears,
昏く抉るんだ 迷いも 束の間の陰
gouging darkly, the hesitation and the fleeting shadow.
想うままで綺麗ごと 抱き締めればと 地べたを窘む世界が 泣き止まぬまま
Embracing pretty ideals as desired,
the world scolding the ground continues to cry unceasingly.
スロウ スロウ その唇で
Slow, slow, with those lips,
深く患った病を 求め咽ぶ
sobbing and yearning for the deeply afflicted illness.
願うまま棘を着こませればと いがらっぽい喉を鳴らす
Hoping to make it wear thorns as desired,
rattling my scratchy throat.
あつらえたごうに乗せ
Laid upon a tailored carriage,
ひっそりと爪を研いでいる
quietly sharpening my claws.
煙さえ我が物に
Making even the smoke my own,
香り纏わせお前の様に
wrapping in fragrance just like you.
この身のどこかに
Somewhere within this body,
生まれ持っていたなら
if I had been born with it—
寄り添わせを前の様に
Let's cuddle close just like before,
この身体のどこかに生まれ持っていたなら
if we were born with it somewhere in our bodies—
酸いも甘いも全部噛む！
I'll bite through all the sweet and sour!
あれれ、地味な苦味に面食らう
Oh my, taken aback by the plain bitterness.
気付けばなにも選べなくなって
Before I knew it, I couldn't choose anything,
僕らは大人になったんだ
and we've grown up.
被害者ヅラは違ったか
Was playing the victim wrong after all?
取り戻そう奪還だ！
Let's take it back, reclamation!
右 見て 左 見て 3回回ってっ
Look right, look left, spin around three times,
にゃん にゃん にゃん
Nyan, nyan, nyan!
右 見て 左 見て 3回回ってっ
Look right, look left, spin around three times,
にゃん にゃん にゃん
Nyan, nyan, nyan!
スワロウ スワロウ その口で
Swallow, swallow, with that mouth,
禍々し纏った迷いも
even the ominous lingering doubts—
求め躓む願いまま
as requested, stumbling as you wish,
棘を着こませればと
if you put on the thorns,
いがらかる喉を鳴らす
it rings out the scratchy throat.
何食わぬ顔さえ
Even with a nonchalant face,
こっそり牙を宿していたい
I secretly want to harbor fangs.
齧り付きたいだけだって
Just wanting to bite into something—
はーい！
Hii!
先ほど流れたVTRの通り、
As you saw in the VTR just now,
なんと、僕の初めての有観客のライブ、
astonishingly, my very first in-person audience live,
猫又おかゆ 1st Live 「ポイズンヤ・シンドローム」 Supported by ブシロードが、
Nekomata Okayu 1st Live "POISONYA SYNDROME" Supported by Bushiroad,
2022年9月30日に立川ステージガーデンで開催できることになりました！やったー！
will be held on September 30, 2022, at Tachikawa Stage Garden! Yay!
えー、ここからたくさんの台本を読むことになるので、噛んだら皆さん笑顔で許してください。
Uh, from here on I'll be reading a lot of script, so if I stumble, please forgive me with a smile.
では、参ります。
Now then, here we go.
キービジュアルイラストは神岡ちろるママ、
The key visual illustration is by Kamioka Chiroru-mama,
ロゴとデザインは富士宮あい先生が担当されました！
and the logo and design were handled by Fujimiya Ai-sensei!
ライブのハッシュタグはおかゆソロライブでお願いします。
The hashtag for the live is #OkayuSoloLive. Please use it!
いやー、やっと発表できたよ！
Man, I'm so glad we could finally announce it!
おにぎりゃーのみんなにはね、なんか色々大変だとか言ってたけど、
To all the Onigirya, I'd been saying things like "it's been various kinds of tough,"
何が大変なのかっていう話まではね、ちょっとできなかったんですけど、
but I couldn't really talk about what was so tough until now.
そうなんです、僕のね、ソロライブがあるんだよみんな！
That's right, I'm having a solo live, everyone!
みんなー！すごいよね！
Everyone! Isn't that amazing?!
えー、このね、描き下ろししていただいたイラストもロゴもめちゃくちゃ可愛いんで、
Um, these newly drawn illustrations and logo are super cute,
舐めるように、舐めるように、皆さん見てくださいね。
so please look at them closely, as if savoring every detail.
超可愛いんで。
They're super cute.
えー、では次読んでいきますよ。
Um, well, I'll read the next part.
この後、21時から現地会場チケットの1次先行抽選、そして配信チケットの販売がスタートします！
Starting tonight at 21:00, the 1st advance lottery for venue tickets and the sale of streaming tickets will begin!
今回現地会場チケット1次先行は、
This time, the 1st advance for venue tickets
ソロライブ公式ファンクラブ先行となるので、
will be the solo live official fan club advance,
お申し込みにはファンクラブへの加入が必要になります。
so joining the fan club will be required to apply.
抽選受付になるので、焦らずに申し込んでね。
Since it's a lottery reception, please apply without rushing.
また、配信チケットはSPWNとLINE LIVE-VIEWINGの2つのプラットフォームを用意してもらいました。
Also, for streaming tickets, SPWN and LINE LIVE-VIEWING are the two platforms prepared for you.
その他、そのほ…そのほじゃない。
Other— other than that... not other than that.
このほかSPWNではデジタルフラワースタンドの受付も開始しています。
In addition, SPWN has also started accepting digital flower stands.
詳細はSPWNの公演ページをチェックしてね。
Check the SPWN performance page for details.
改めましてチケットの申し込みURLなど詳細は特設ホームページやソロライブプロダクションイベント総合Twitterをチェックしてください。
Once again, please check the special homepage or the solo live production event official Twitter for details such as ticket application URLs.
そして、ライブといえばライブグッズ！
And speaking of live, live merchandise!
各グッズサイトで今回のライブグッズが発表されております。
The live merchandise has been announced on each merchandise site.
日本のお客さんはSPWNの公演ページで、海外のお客さんはGeekJackさんで買えます。
Japanese customers can buy on SPWN's performance page, and overseas customers can buy on GeekJack.
なお、応援セット、Tシャツ、アクリルプレートライト、フェイスタオルは先行発動アイテムになり…
Furthermore, the support set, T-shirt, acrylic plate light, and face towel are advance shipping items...
ね、選ばれた よりすぐりのね、アイテムたちなんですよ。
These are carefully selected items.
僕もいっぱい考えたし、あの運営さんとも一緒に
I thought about them a lot, and together with management
どうしようかどうしようかって考えて決めたものなので、めちゃくちゃ可愛いです。
we discussed what to do and decided on them, so they're super cute!
はーい！
Yay!
では、え、ライブ参戦に必須のアイテム、アクリルプレートライト、Tシャツ、フェイスタオルが
Now, the must-have items for attending the live: the acrylic plate light, T-shirt, and face towel
セットになりました！
come as a set!
特典でチケットケースとチケット風ステッカーがついてくるから絶対ゲットしてね！
It comes with a ticket case and ticket-style sticker as a bonus, so be sure to get it!
え、ぽいずにゃ〜しんどろーむアクリルプレートライト、え、Tシャツ、フェイスタオルですね、こちら。めちゃくちゃ可愛くない？
And here are the "Poisonya Syndrome" acrylic plate light, T-shirt, and face towel. Aren't they super cute?
フェイスタオルのデザインもめっちゃ迷ったし、
I struggled a lot with the face towel design too,
Tシャツも1匹ね、ここら辺に黄緑色の猫のワンポイントがついてるんだけど、これをもうちょっと内側にするか、もうちょっと外側にするか、もうめっちゃ迷ったの！
and for the T-shirt, there's a yellowish-green cat point on it, but I agonized over whether to place it a bit more inward or outward!
もうそういうね、細かいところまでいっぱい悩んで作ったデザインとなっておりますので、よろしくお願いします！
I put a lot of thought into every little detail like that, so I hope you'll check them out!
では次まいりましょう。
Now, let's move on to the next one.
ぽいずにゃ〜しんどろーむグッズ、え、こちらはTシャツ、アクリルプレートライト、フェイスタオル。
"Poisonya Syndrome" goods: the T-shirt, acrylic plate light, and face towel.
え、こちらはバラで買うこともできます。
You can also buy these individually.
はい。なので、ま、ちょっと全部は買うの難しいかなっていう人でも、バラでね、ちょっと欲しいものだけ買うっていうのもできるようになっているのでよろしくお願いします！
Yes! So even if it's hard for you to buy the whole set, you can buy just the items you want individually, so please check it out!
では、次の画像行きます。
Now, let's go to the next image.
ほい！
Here we go!
え、こちらはですね、ロゴラバーキーホルダー、BIG缶バッジスタンド、アクリルスタンドとなっております。
And here we have the logo rubber keychain, big can badge stand, and acrylic stand.
可愛いね！もうスタンドも飾ってほしいし、このロゴラバーキーホルダーつけていつもでお散歩してほしいし、このBIG缶バッジスタンドは飾れるようにスタンドになってるからどこにでも飾れちゃう。
They're so cute! I want you to display the stands, wear the logo rubber keychain when you go out, and since the big can badge stand is designed to stand up, you can display it anywhere.
パソコンの横とかにも置けるし、もう僕のグッズを飾ってる棚がある人はもうそれだけで飾れるようになっています。
You can put it next to your computer, and if you have a shelf displaying my goods, you can display it right there.
え、いずれのグッズも購入の際に各グッズサイトに書かれている注意事項をチェックしてください。
Please make sure to check the notes listed on each merchandise site when purchasing any of the items.
そして、今回ライブグッズは現地会場では販売されないので、ぜひグッズサイトをチェックしてみてください！
Also, please note that live goods will not be sold at the actual venue, so be sure to check the merchandise site!
また、今回特別協賛の株式会社ブシロード様からお知らせがあります。
Also, we have an announcement from our special sponsor, Bushiroad Inc.
現地に来場していただいたお客様へは、入場時に今回のライブキービジュアルのデザインを使用したリバース！PRカードをプレゼントします！
To customers attending the venue, we will present a Reバース PR card featuring the design of this live's key visual upon entry!
ぜひ手に入れてね！
Be sure to get your hands on it!
そして最後に、どん！
And finally, ta-da!
先日発表した僕のファーストアルバムのタイトルは「ぽいずにゃ〜しんどろーむ」になります！
The title of my 1st album announced the other day is "Poisonya Syndrome"!
ライブと一緒です。
It's the same as the live.
かわいい！
It's so cute!
ライブとアルバムの名前別々にしようかなとか考えたんだけど、よりね、みんなの印象に残ればなということで同じ名前にさせていただきました。
I thought about giving the live and the album different names, but I wanted it to leave a stronger impression on everyone, so I made them the same name.
アルバムジャケットとトラックリストも公開しました。
The album jacket and tracklist have also been revealed.
ライブのキービジュアルと同じく、アルバムジャケットのイラストは神岡ちろるママ、ロゴのデザインは藤米田愛先生が担当されました。
Just like the live key visual, the album jacket illustration was done by Kamioka Chirol Mama, and the logo design was handled by Fujinome Ai-sensei.
今までに発表した「モグモグYUMMY!」「デタバレ猫」「毒の王子様」「アデュー、サロー」を含む合計12曲が収録されています。
A total of 12 songs are included, including previously announced tracks like "Mogumog YUMMY!", "Detabare Neko", "Doku no Oujisama", and "Adieu, Salut".
もうね、全部この曲大好きで、で、僕の大好きな人たちにお願いしてるのね。だから早くみんなに聴いてほしいな。
I love every single song, and I asked people I really love to work on them. So I want everyone to hear them as soon as possible!
マジで早く聴いてほしい。まあ、1から12番まで全部説明すると多分10時ぐらいになっちゃうんで、まあ、ここのページね、スクショなりなんなりしてちょっと見返してもらえればなと思います。
I seriously want you to hear them soon. Well, if I explain all 12 songs from 1 to 12, it'll probably take about 10 hours, so I hope you can take a screenshot of this page and review it later.
では、アルバムのハッシュタグは「ぽいずにゃ〜しんどろーむ」です。
Now, the album hashtag is "#PoisonyaSyndrome".
おかゆソロライブと合わせてどんどんどんどんツイートしちゃってください。
Please tweet away along with the Okayu solo live!
改めて、はー、言い切った！
Once again, phew, I said it all!
情報ももりだくさんだったね、みんな。
There was so much info, everyone!
嬉しい？嬉しい？
Are you happy? Are you happy?
僕はね、僕はもうすごく嬉しいし、今日という日にみんなにね、発表できたのがすごく嬉しい。
I'm so, so happy, and I'm so happy I was able to announce this to everyone on this very day.
ずっとずっと言いたかった！7月24日が本当に待ち遠しかったよ、みんな。
I've wanted to say it for so, so long! I've been really looking forward to July 24th, everyone.
ねえ、みんなありがとね、見えてるよ。ありがとありがと！
Hey, thank you everyone, I see you. Thank you, thank you!
ええと、ソロライブの開催、キービジュアルやロゴの発表、現地や配信チケットやグッズ情報、現地の来場者特典やアルバム情報などなど、ライブの情報に関しては直接ホームページもオープンしています。公演の注意事項などもこちらにアップされているのでぜひ見てね。
Um, for live information such as solo live dates, key visual and logo reveals, venue and streaming tickets, merchandise info, venue attendee perks, and album info, the official website is now open. Notices and precautions for the performance are also posted there, so please check it out.
ライブ開催まで約2ヶ月、僕もみんなと会えるのが待ち遠しいです！
It's about two months until the live, and I can't wait to see everyone!
どんどんビッグニュースが
More big news is coming up,
発表される予定なので楽しみにしててね！
so please look forward to it!
以上、猫又おかゆでした！
That's all from Nekomata Okayu!
バイバーイ！
Bye-bye!
香る惑わせお前のように
この体のどこかに生ませ持っていたなら
何もかもも触って毒毒毒
痛いようなうまさかと鍵回られも仕様が喉から手が出るほど毒毒毒
初め初めと構えていた
諸刃の刃でじっといられるのなら
野党を向かい
座ろう座ろうその唇でどかかすらあった止まり木を求めず暴む目が名前ばかりをこなせればと野良がかかるのを治す
何かを抜わぬ香りさえこっそり牙をやっていたいかじりつきだいらげて